(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-25T00:58:51.713476",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
What's up!
I am Chaos, the End of Days,
a steel rose trapped in the cage of ice,
your best friend Hakos Baelz,
from hololive English -Promise-!
WITNESS ME!
やったー！
Yay!
Happy 5 years, everyone!
5年！
5 years!
ヤバくないですか？
Isn't that crazy?
みんな、ヤバいですね、5年！
Everyone, 5 years is crazy!
Thank you so much for joining me today
for my 5th anniversary stream!
I can't believe it's been 5 years!
We're also in a very nostalgic place...
いや、ここもね、ちょっと
Well, this place too,
懐かしい場所に来ましたよね？
we came to a nostalgic place, didn't we?
This is the stage from my 3D debut stream,
and I thought it'd be fitting to return back here for
my BIG 5TH!
Yes!
Back in the Fun Zone, back in the Fun Zone!
We're gonna be hanging out with some awesome guests!
I can't believe some of the guests that...
very graciously agreed to appear today!
Maybe some games, maybe some singing...
And that's not all!
As you may or may not already know,
HUGE announcements,
with an S,
are coming your way, so make sure you stick to the very end!
えー、まとめですね、
Um, to summarize,
5周年お祝い
for this 5th anniversary celebration,
ということなんで、えーっと、
and since it's for that, um...
ゲストさんも、あの、すごい
the guests too, um, amazing
ゲストさんが来てくれてますので、
guests have come to join us,
本当自分も信じられないぐらい、えーっと、
so I myself can hardly believe it, um,
楽しみにしてます！
I'm really looking forward to it!
ちょっとゲームやってみたりとか、
We might play some games, or...
まあ、歌もね、ちょっと
well, singing too, maybe...
あるかな？ちょっと分からないですけど、あっ！
will there be? I'm not sure, but ah!
重大発表も
Huge announcements too,
たくさんありますので、
there are lots of them,
最後まで見ててください！
so please watch until the end!
And please make sure to share your thoughts on the stream
using, what is it, #BaeBig5th!
#BaeBig5th!
I'll be checking all your posts after the stream, so don't...
Get the prize!
そしてですね、配信の感想はハッシュタグ #BaeBig5th を使って...
And also, please post your impressions of the stream using the hashtag #BaeBig5th...
投稿してください。配信が終わったら、僕もみんなもね、投稿チェックするので、たくさんの感想を待ってますよー！
After the stream ends, everyone and I will check your posts, so we're waiting for lots of feedback!
おねがいしまーす！
Please do!
Without further ado, let's jump right into our first segment! 行こう！
Without further ado, let's jump right into our first segment! Let's go!
ベイちゃん！ ハッピー5thアニバーサリー！
Bae-chan! Happy 5th Anniversary!
セレーブレイト！ セレーブレイト！ おめでとう！
Celebrate! Celebrate! Congratulations!
ベイちゃん！ Yeah! Happy for you, right!
Bae-chan! Yeah! Happy for you, right!
I'm so happy I'm with all my friends today.
あの、自己紹介お願いしてもいいですか？
Um, could you all please introduce yourselves?
あたし？ Okay, okay.
Me? Okay, okay.
みなさん！ It's me, Mori Calliope from Hololive English -Myth-!
Everyone! It's me, Mori Calliope from Hololive English -Myth-!
破滅は高校生活... death death! I'm Shinigami, Reaper, songwriter, and also best friend!
How matches whole cold... death death! I'm Shinigami, Reaper, songwriter, and also best friend!
Bae is my best friend! Bae!
That's who's best!
あ！ッス！ I'm スバル！ Hololive JP second generation, and...
Ah! 'Su! I'm Subaru! Hololive JP second generation, and...
Best of... best friend!
Wait, wait, wait! You said 'I'm your best friend, Baelz Hakos!'
So you're not my best friend, you're her best friend!
まあ、あの、ベストフレンド... みんなベストフレンドだって！ みんなベストフレンドなのよ！
Well, um, best friend... Everyone is a best friend! Everyone is a best friend!
アンド、そして...
And, next...
Hi! Good morning, afternoon, evening! WAH! Ninomae Ina'nis from Hololive English -Myth-! I also want to be Bae's...
Best friend! Bae's best friend!
Yaaay! さすが！
Yaaay! As expected!
そして！ こんぴー！ Hololive 4th generation, 常闇トワ様です！ イエーイ！
And! Konpii! Hololive 4th generation, Tokoyami Towa-sama here! Yay!
私こそが、えー、Baeのナンバーワン・ベストフレンドです！
I am indeed Bae's number one best friend!
No no no! All of my best friends are here! Everyone is the best!
この子がナンバーワン... この子がナンバーワン、ベジマイト！
This child is number one... This child is number one, BAE-GEMITE!
Bae-gemite! おおー！
Bae-gemite! Ooh!
Bae-gemiteです！ でっけー！
It's Bae-gemite! It's huge!
What is this? What is this なんですけど...
What is this? 'What is this?', but...
これ、あの、ベジマイトです。なんと今日ですね、えーと、僕の5周年なんで...
This is, um, Vegemite. Today is, well, my 5th anniversary...
It's my 5th anniversary! I bring to you BAE-GEMITE Extravaganza Part 1!
僕のベジマイト大企画へようこそ！ また来た、ベジマイト！
Welcome to my big Vegemite project! Vegemite came again!
お前、ベジマイト好きすぎ！ はい、ベジマイト代表なんで、はい。お願いします！
You like Vegemite way too much! Yes, well, I'm the Vegemite representative, so yeah. Please treat me well!
えっと、まあ一応説明しますが、はい。 BAE-GEMITE... It's inspired by the greatest food of all, Vegemite.
Well, I'll explain it just in case. Yes. BAE-GEMITE... It's inspired by the greatest food of all, Vegemite.
Packed with Vitamin B, it truly is the ultimate spread. In fact...
It wouldn't be an exaggeration to say that everyone in my country grew up eating it!
And today, I'd like all of my guests to experience the true greatness that is Vegemite first-hand!
これはなんとですね、我が国への... 誇りである！
This is, amazingly... the pride of our country!
Look, look! Look at Calli's face! Why?!
But why?!
Today we have a very special rendition of BAE-GEMITE...
BAE-GEMITE SHOWDOWN!
ゲームをやりたいと思います！ はい！
I'd like to play a game! Yes!
ベストフレンド... ベストフレンドを決める...
Best friend... To decide the best friend...
えっ、ゲームをやって、whoever loses will discover that, you know, they might be missing something, you know?
Um, we'll play a game, and whoever loses will discover that, you know, they might be missing something, you know?
Do you know what it is, Calli? Do you have any idea what they could be missing if they lose?
Yeah, that's right! NUTRITION!
栄養が足りてない！ もし負けた方がね、栄養が足りてないってこと！
Lacking nutrition! If someone loses, it means they lack nutrition!
そう！ 僕はですね、やっぱりベジマイトで育てられたので...
Right! As for me, I was raised on Vegemite after all, so...
僕に負けた人が、ちょっとね、ちょっと栄養を増やして...
So the person who loses to me needs to increase their nutrition a bit...
え、Same tall, same tall, nearly same tall! いやいやいや！ こっちじゃなくて、これですよ、これ！
Huh, same tall, same tall, nearly same tall! No no no! Not this, it's this! This!
これ！
This!
Oh god. Not enough muscle!
Okay, なるほどね。ってことです！
Okay, I see. So that's how it is!
Is everyone ready?
Ready! Are you ready?
Bring it on! Yeah, I guess we're ready.
じゃあ、The stage of trials, manifest yourselves! FUNZONE!
Well then! The stage of trials, manifest yourselves! FUNZONE!
え！？ うわー！
What?! Wow!
すごい！ I didn't know you could do that!
Amazing! I didn't know you could do that!
急に出てきてるよ！ 制作の力です！
It suddenly appeared! That's the power of production!
これが…！ レースコース！
This is...! A race track!
So, the game we're playing today is: the Ultimate Tricycle Race!
Tricycle, 3, 2, 1, 0, レース！
Tricycle, 3, 2, 1, 0, Race!
です！ 出てきた！ Yeah!
Yep! It appeared! Yeah!
The rules are very simple. We'll all ride a tricycle and complete two laps around the course we've set up here in the Fun Zone.
And the challenge is to see if you can beat my time! 僕より速ければ、勝てるって感じです！
And the challenge is to see if you can beat my time! Basically, if you're faster than me, you win!
うわー！ Wait, wait, wait!
Wow! Wait, wait, wait!
倒さなくてもいいってことだよね？ あ、まあ、うん。
Meaning we don't have to beat you directly? Ah, well, yeah.
Wait, so if we ALL win? No, one... まあ、一応… そうですね。
Wait, so if we ALL win? No, one... Well, technically... Yes, that's right.
If you win... If you win... え、勝ったら？
If you win... If you win... Wait, if we win?
ということで、ちょっと早速始めたいと思いますが！ 準備はいいですか？
So with that, I'd like to get started right away! Are you ready?
Okay! Everyone ready? はい！
Okay! Everyone ready? Yes!
じゃあ、先輩お二人方、お礼… お願いします！
Well then, senior members, please give us your pre-game comments!
我等（かまん）とは！ 三輪車… Come on!
"Kamanto" is! Tricycle... Come on!
ぶー！ ぶー！ Ladies, ladies, ladies!
Vroom! Vroom! Ladies, ladies, ladies!
Okay, okay! ぶー！ ぶー！ ぶー！
Okay, okay! Vroom! Vroom! Vroom!
大空スバル：圧倒の声量！しかし三輪車との相性は未知数！「トワには負けねえ！ 俺が勝つ！」
[Oozora Subaru: POWERFUL VOICE! But How Will She Handle the Tricycle?!] "I won't lose to Towa! I'm going to win!"
常闇トワ：器用さは随一！テクニカルな走りに期待！「スバルのことは眼中にありません。自分との戦いです。」
[Tokoyami Towa: Top-Tier Skill! Can She Pull Off a Technical Ride?!] "Subaru isn't even on my radar. This is a battle with myself."
じゃんけんしたいです！ あ、そうね、Okay.
I want to do rock-paper-scissors! Ah, right, okay.
内側が有利なんじゃないかなと。
I think the inside track gives an advantage.
So we're going to do Rock, Paper, Scissors to find out who gets to ride on the inside! じゃ、どうぞ！
So we're going to do Rock, Paper, Scissors to find out who gets to ride on the inside! Go ahead then!
Rock, Paper, Scissors, Shoot!
やったー！ イェーイ！
Yay! Yeah!
Nice! 素晴らしいです！
Nice! Wonderful!
じゃあ、トワ様が内側ですね。 そういうことですね。
So Towa-sama gets the inside track. That's how it is.
じゃあお二人、お二人からちょっと意気込みをお願いしていいですか？ はい。
Now then, could the two of you share your enthusiasm? Yes.
I'm a winner! Winner!
ウィナーさん！ ウィナーさん！ あーウィナー！
Ms. Wiener! Ms. Wiener! Ah, wiener!
ウィナーじゃない！ I'm a winner!
That's a wiener, not winner! I'm a winner!
パくってんじゃないよ！ 痛い！ 痛い！
Don't rip off my line! Ouch! Ouch!
じゃあ乗ってください！ Bae, Bae, Bae!
Okay, please get on! Bae, Bae, Bae!
Yes, this battle, BOOM, okay?
BOOM, okay! BOOM, okay!
You can interfere with each other if you want. Friendly fire allowed!
Oh brother! But you just can't get off your tricycle.
ちょっと三輪車から降りるのはちょっとダメ。 ああ、なるほどね。
Getting off the tricycle is not allowed. Ah, I see.
でも妨害はOKです。 妨害OK？ やばい！ 妨害される！
But sabotaging is OK. Sabotaging is OK? Oh no, I'm gonna get sabotaged!
準備はいいですか？ 行くよ！ Here we go!
Are you ready? Here we go! Here we go!
3, 2, 1, GO!
キャー！ ごめんごめん！
Aaargh! Sorry, sorry!
何してんの？！
What are you doing?!
スバル先輩がインコース取ってる！
Subaru-senpai took the inside track!
Go, go, go! 2回目！ 2回目！
Go, go, go! Second lap! Second lap!
トワ様！ 行け！
Towa-sama! Go!
速い！ 速い！ 速い！
Fast! Fast! Fast!
やばい、やばい！ ゴール！
Oh no, oh no! Goal!
行け！ トワ様！ 行け、行け！
Go, Towa-sama! Go, go!
イェーイ！ おめでとうございます！
Yeah! Congratulations!
Congratulations! I'm a winner!
Well, technically it wasn't just a battle between them...
一応タイムアタックなんで、後で…
It's technically a time attack, so later...
森カリオペ：ラップだけじゃない！華麗なライディングにも期待！
[Mori Calliope: More Than Just Rap! Expect a Stylish Ride!] "I feel I'm really well prepared for this race. You know, I'm a 4-time champ of Underworld University Tricycle Marathon..."
一伊那爾栖：WAHパワー全開！？意外なスピードに期待！
[Ninomae Ina'nis: WAH Power?! Unexpected Speed!] "Win or lose, I get to eat Bae's cookie. Yeah."
All righty! Seems like Calli and Ina are all set. Are you two feeling confident?
Oh! ごめんごめん、ちっちゃいね、イナちゃん！
Oh! Sorry, sorry, Ina-chan is so small!
ちっちゃい！ Yeah, Ina and Calli, we'd never fight.
So small! Yeah, Ina and Calli, we'd never fight.
You guys ready? Can we get a one comment from the both of you, please?
私、勝つ！ 勝つ？ 勝つ？
Me win! Win? Win?
It's not as funny...
カツさん！カツさん！
Katsu-san! Katsu-san!
カツさんだ！カツさんだ！
It's Katsu-san! It's Katsu-san!
ウィーンさんとカツさん！
Wien-san and Katsu-san!
Ina is hungry~
お腹空いた...
I'm hungry...
カツを食べろ！カツを！
Eat katsu! Eat katsu!
何カツさん言います？
What Katsu-san are you talking about?
カツ丼？ カツ丼？ カツを...
Katsudon? Katsudon? Katsu...
カツ丼
Katsudon.
やばい、止めて！止めてってば！
Oh no, stop it! Stop it I said!
準備OKですか？
Are you ready?
Who's using the inner and who's using the outer?
Outside is apparently stronger, so whoever wins gets outside.
Rock, paper, scissors, shoot!
Calliは外側！
Calli gets the outside!
I get the feeling this position is best!
I don't know, I got a bad feeling about this one...
Alright, you guys ready?
Alright, here we go! 3, 2, 1, go!
いけー！ Let's go, Ina!
Go! Let's go, Ina!
Out of my way!
There will be no context for me!
Ina, 頑張れ！
Do your best, Ina!
No one's gonna get in front of me!
Look at that!
That's the first time I've exercised in two years...
Ina, 大丈夫？
Ina, are you okay?
I'm okay! I'm okay!
Ina先輩...
Ina-senpai...
Wow, with the four of them completing the race...
...I think we should announce the times before I try.
4人終わったんで、タイムを発表したいと思います！
Since all four have finished, I'd like to announce the times!
じゃあ、最初はスバル先輩！
First up is Subaru-senpai!
タイムは何でしょうーか？
What is her time?!
28.85秒！
28.85 seconds!
速っ！結構いいんじゃない？これ！
So fast! Isn't that pretty good?!
速いっすね！ じゃあ、次はトワ様！
That's fast! Next up is Towa-sama!
タイムは...
The time is...
35.63秒！
35.63 seconds!
結構... でも速いっすよ！
That's... but still pretty fast!
次は Calliope Mori! Your time is...
Next is Calliope Mori! Your time is...
36.72!
I'm fast!
えっ、速っ！
Wait, so fast!
で、最後はイナ！ Your time is...
And lastly, Ina! Your time is...
38.44!
でもさ...
But still...
え、でもみんな速くね？
Wait, isn't everyone fast?
つまり、Bae-chan, maybe you're also a little slow like we are.
So, Bae-chan, maybe you're also a little slow like we are.
40秒ぐらいでお願いしたいところか...
We'd like you to get around 40 seconds...
So I have to beat... みんな食べれるタイムだったら...
So I have to beat... If it's a time where everyone gets to eat...
28秒切れればいいってことだな！
You just need to beat 28 seconds!
Be faster than 28 seconds.
Well, with that being said, it's my turn!
ベジマイトパワーで驚異のタイムを見せられるか！
Can Vegemite power deliver a blazing fast time!?
ということで、ベイビーの準備ができたようです！
And with that, it seems Bae is ready!
一番似合ってるわ！
It suits her the most!
Just fit! Just fit!
普段から乗ってるでしょ？
You usually ride this, don't you?
普段乗ってねぇよ！
I don't usually ride this!
どうですか？意気込みをお願いします！
How do you feel? Give us your enthusiasm!
いやもう、全てはベジマイトのためである。僕は勝つ！
Well, everything is for the Vegemite. I will win!
とんでもないよ！ベジマイト好きすぎるだろ！
Unbelievable! You love Vegemite way too much!
ベジマイトから生まれたんじゃない？
Weren't you born from Vegemite?
だからBae？
Is that why you're Bae?
だからBaeですよ！
That's why I'm Bae!
どうせ勝つだし、大丈夫！
I'm gonna win anyway, so it's fine!
そんなこと言ったらさ、トワが... あ、すみません...
If you say that, Towa will... Ah, sorry...
Sorry, you can't cross! There's an accident!
There's an accident! You have to go around.
Sorry, you can't cross here. Sorry, go home!
Go home! Go home!
ということで、じゃあ。これで順位決まりますから、我々...
So, with this, the ranking will be decided...
ベジマイトとどうなるかというのが、これで決まりますから。
...and what happens with the Vegemite will be decided by this.
位置についていいですか？ - はい！
Are you ready at the starting line? - Yes!
Here we go!
Go!
2, 1... Go!
うわ、なんか...あ、ヤバい！ヤバい！なんかマジで必死...
Whoa, she's trying so hard!
ヤバい、ガチの顔してる！シリアス面！シリアス面！
Look at her super serious face! Look at that serious face!
ちょっと！ヤバい！
Wait, this is crazy!
速い...！ちょっと...
She's so fast! Wait...
Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait!
Wait! Wait!
Wait! - ねぇー！
Wait! - Hey!
イェーイ！
Yay!
速い...速いぞ、ベイビー。
Fast... That was so fast, baby!
速すぎた、私。
I was way too fast.
速すぎるだろ！
Isn't that way too fast?!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
じゃあ、発表行きますか！
Alright, shall we go to the results announcement?
はい！はい！
Yes! Yes!
さっきの順番でどこを食べるか...
Based on our order earlier, who eats what...
僕のタイム、お願いします！
Show my time, please!
おお〜！
Whoa!
全員、ベジマイト食べます！
Everyone is eating Vegemite!
She's excited about that.
She's so excited about that!
お調子者すぎる、マジで！
She's getting way too carried away, seriously!
She's so hyped about that.
We gonna prepare the... Not a punishment, it's a prize!
We're gonna prepare... It's not a punishment, it's a prize!
みんなも心の中で優勝なんで。これはプレゼントです！
In everyone's hearts, you're all winners. So this is a present!
なんか言ってる！イイように言ってるだけだよ！
She's just trying to frame it nicely!
なのでみんな、ちょっと待ってね！ We gonna get the place prepared...
So everyone, please wait a bit! We gonna get the place prepared...
...to taste some Vegemite!
ベジマイト食べます！
We're eating Vegemite!
Woah!
The dishes are ready.
You know, when I first had these four enter...
...I knew from the get go, they were lacking nutrition.
...I knew from the get-go, they were lacking nutrition.
やっぱりね、この4人が入った瞬間に、もう分かってました。
As expected, the moment these four walked in, I already knew.
What are you talking about?
栄養が足りてない。栄養が足りてない！
Lacking nutrition. You're lacking nutrition!
なので、こちらを準備しております。
So, I have prepared this for you all.
You know, everyone is lacking nutrition. And what is the most important meal of the day?
That's right, breakfast!
朝ご飯が一番大事な食事なんで、今日は皆様に栄養たっぷり...
Breakfast is the most important meal, so today I've prepared...
...朝ご飯を用意しております。
...a nutrition-packed breakfast for you.
A very delicious dish! Very delicious!
Very delicious? - Very delicious dish.
Very delicious? - A very delicious dish.
You can take off... - お〜！
You can take off... - Ooh!
ちょっと1つずつご紹介させてください。
Let me introduce them one by one.
まずはですね、生ベジマイトありますね。
First off, we have plain Vegemite here.
えっと、これは後でね、トワ様と...
Umm, this is for later... Towa-sama and...
イナは食べたことないんで、1回ちょっとね生で...
...Ina have never had it before, so just once plain...
...味でね、ちょっとだけ...
...just a little bit to taste it.
で、これはもう健康的な朝ご飯を用意しております。
And here, I've prepared a healthy breakfast.
まずはね、パン！パンにベジマイト塗っております。
First is bread! Spread with Vegemite on top.
これはまあ、オーストラリア定番の朝ご飯です。This is a very traditional Australian breakfast...
This is a staple Australian breakfast. This is a very traditional Australian breakfast...
...with bread and Vegemite.
で、次に参ります。味噌汁でございます。
Moving on to the next one, we have miso soup.
When we speak of Japanese breakfast, we think of miso soup.
朝ご飯と言えば...まあ、本当に豪華！
And speaking of breakfast... well, a truly luxurious one!
朝ご飯と言ったら、お寿司ですね！
Speaking of breakfast, it's sushi!
朝から食わねぇよ、お寿司！
Nobody eats sushi in the morning!
朝から寿司食わねぇ...
Nobody eats sushi for breakfast...
I just need someone to agree with me that Vegemite and sushi is amazing.
ちょっとね、認めてほしくて。寿司とベジマイト、マジで似合うんだって！
I just want you to admit it. Sushi and Vegemite actually go together so well!
嘘だ！どこにつけたの、ベジマイト？
No way! Where did you put the Vegemite?
ワサビみたいに、ちょっと裏に...
Like wasabi, just a little underneath...
嘘だ！ワサビじゃない！ - ワサビの代わりに...
Liar! That's not wasabi! - Instead of wasabi...
なんかこれオープンした瞬間から、なん科学...大丈夫？
The moment this opened, I felt like sneezing... Are you okay?
なので、ちょっとトワ様とイナはベジマイト初なんで、ちょっと生で...
So since it's Towa-sama and Ina's first time with Vegemite, just a bit plain...
Or like, you'll get rid of the taste of any other food after.
No, no, no! Just a little bit. Have a little courage.
いただきます。
Bon appétit.
Try it! Try it! Okay, Towa-sama first. Oh, she's going for it!
ん？普通？
Huh? Normal?
え？めっちゃいい顔した！
Eh? You made such a face!
まあ、いけなくはない。
Well, it's not impossible to eat.
いい顔！ちょっとスゴいな...
Nice face! That's pretty impressive...
「いけなくはない」なるほどですね。はい、OKです。じゃあ次！
"Not impossible," I see. Alright, cool. Next!
Let's go!
Don't be scary! 恐れるな！
Don't be scared! Don't be scared!
Don't be scary, don't be scary. It's good! It tastes so good!
Okay, 味噌、味噌...
Okay, miso, miso...
行きます。平気だよ！
Here I go. I'll be fine!
行きます。
Here I go.
It's not that bad. / See! あー、さすが！
It's not that bad. / See! Ah, as expected!
Not that bad. Pretty good. Not that bad equals pretty good.
美味しいでしょ？
Delicious, right?
うん、悪くない。
Yeah, not bad.
悪くない！いける！
Not bad! It works!
Would you choose to eat it?
If I had absolutely no other side dishes, and only a bowl of rice... possibly.
じゃあちょっと、みんなの朝ごはんタイム行きますか！
Alright then, shall we move on to everyone's breakfast time?
じゃあ最初パンでおねがいします。
Let me start with bread, please.
パンで。 / はい。
With bread. / Yes.
いただきます。
Bon appétit.
See, it's good with bread. / See! 美味しいでしょ！
See, it's good with bread. / See! Tasty, right?
美味しいですよねー！
It's delicious, right?
You need bread though, or something.
Oh, good! / See!
This breakfast... / しょっぱい！
This breakfast... / Salty!
It is pretty salty. Yeah, it is pretty salty.
美味しいですよね？ほらほら！全然バツじゃない！
It's delicious, right? Look, look! It's not a penalty at all!
ちょっと味が濃い... / 味が濃いっすね。まあそうですね。
The flavor is a bit strong... / The flavor is strong. Well, yeah.
パン食べた後にちょっと飲みたいんじゃないですか？
After eating bread, don't you want to drink something?
飲みたい！飲みたい！ / じゃあ次はお味噌汁お願いします！
Want to drink! Want to drink! / Next, miso soup please!
Redo... Three stars... out of 10? Out of 5!
Out of 5, but I mean...
Miso soup... You know, everyone keeps saying that Vegemite tastes like...
お味噌汁美味しい！ / Oh, good!
Miso soup is delicious! / Oh, good!
お味噌汁美味しい！ / Very good! Very good!
Miso soup is delicious! / Very good! Very good!
Well, a savory item.
Don't get mad at me... Yo, she's gonna kill me.
I don't taste it at all. なんか味が...
I don't taste it at all. Somehow the taste...
しない。普通のお味噌汁。
...is non-existent. It's just normal miso soup.
うまいでしょ！美味しいでしょ！
Good, right? Delicious, right?
これ合格です。
This is a pass.
あ、合格！ありがとうございます！
Ah, a pass! Thank you very much!
最後ちょっと本当に... 最後キツ...
Lastly, really... the last one is tough...
魚の方でちょっと食べてほしいんですけど...
I'd like you to try it with fish...
いや、これ嫌ー！ / 絶対に美味しい！
No, I hate this! / It's definitely delicious!
It's got no soy sauce. / Calli!
That's not the fish!
Tamago! / Eat the salmon!
No! I want tamago sushi!
Then different soy sauce. / もう醤油につけなくて大丈夫です！
Then different soy sauce. / You don't need to dip it in soy sauce anymore!
醤油につけなくていいの？ / しょっぱいんで！
Don't need to dip it in soy sauce? / Because it's salty!
どう？Is it a go? / It's fine.
How is it? Is it a go? / It's fine.
Oh!
次、次誰行きます？はい！はい！
Next, who's next? Yes! Yes!
わー！いただきます。
Wow! Thank you for the food.
ん〜！微妙〜！
Mmm... questionable!
いや、違う違う違う！美味しい、美味しい！
No, wait wait wait! It's delicious, it's delicious!
最初美味しいの顔してた！ / Two stars.
You made a 'delicious' face at first! / Two stars.
では、いただきます。
Well then, bon appétit.
そうだよね！分かるよ！
Right? I get it!
I think so too. / I think so だよ。
I think so too. / It's "I think so."
このBGMほんとタイミング...
This background music timing is really...
いやいやいや、ノーベジマイトじゃない？なんか...
No no no, isn't it no-Vegemite? Like...
ベジマイトなくない？ / ベジマイトない。There is no Vegemite.
There's no Vegemite? / No Vegemite.
え、だから Put on... On Vegemite!
Eh, so put on... On Vegemite!
え、でも今中に入れたよ？
Eh, but I put it inside just now?
中だと分かんないんだって！ / You gotta put it directly.
They say they can't tell if it's inside! / You gotta put it directly.
ダイレクトベジマイトしないと！
You gotta do direct Vegemite!
あ、そうだよね。そっち？OK OK.
Ah, right. That way? OK, OK.
じゃあ、イカ！ / そうすると星2になるよ。
Then, squid! / Then it becomes 2 stars.
Let's go!
She looks so cute... Why?
イカもいいかな。 / 大丈夫っすよ。
Squid is fine too. / It's fine.
なんか... / どうしました？
Somehow... / What happened?
お寿司買って... / うん。 / 冷蔵庫に...
Bought sushi... / Yeah. / Put it in the fridge...
ちょっと入れて... / うん。
...for a bit... / Yeah.
食べたの忘れて...
I forgot I ate it...
スクリーン越しに食べてる感じの...
It feels like I'm eating through the screen...
味がする。
It actually tastes like it.
寿司やん！
That's just sushi!
寿司や！
It's sushi!
寿司や！いやでもベジマイトの匂いが...
It is sushi! But the smell of Vegemite...
あ！やばい！ツボに...
Oh no, I'm choking!
ツッココ美味しいな～
Tuk-koko is delicious~
やったー！
Yay!
ワン... ワンスター、ツースター、スリースター...
One... One star, two stars, three stars...
Don't say out of how many. How many stars? How many?
Five stars!
Five stars out of five.
Out of ten! Out of ten! No!
Out of vibe ですよね。
It's out of vibes, right?
やったー！
Yay!
僕が食べた時めっちゃ美味しかったんスけど、なんで？
When I ate it, it was super delicious though. Why?
ハコスの舌 is crazy なのか...
Is Bae's tongue just crazy, or...
ま、味は、ま、一旦良しとして...
Well, putting the taste aside for now...
栄養はたっぷり入ってます！
It's packed with nutrients!
And I think... ちょっとね、前に...行きましょうか。
And I think... shall we move to the front?
ちょっと、みんな...前に出る...
Let's everyone step to the front...
Thank you for the food. - You're welcome! ごちそうさまでした！ありがとうございました！
Thank you for the food. - You're welcome! Thank you for the meal!
どっちがいい？どっちがいい？オッケー！
Which way is good? Which way? Okay!
ほらほらもう栄養の成果... 栄養ダンス！
Look at the power of nutrition! A nutrition dance!
本当に楽しかったです！ありがとうございました！
It was really fun! Thank you so much!
Thank you! I'm so happy that all my, you know, lovely friends could join me...
Thank you! I'm so happy that all my lovely friends could join me...
...and best friends... and celebrate my 5th anniversary! And...
...and best friends, to celebrate my 5th anniversary! And...
And, you know, not only I get to celebrate it with Vegemite, but also with these lovely ladies, and also... I have a huge announcement!
Not only do I get to celebrate it with Vegemite, but also with these lovely ladies! And also, I have a huge announcement!
告知があります！
I have an announcement!
Big announcement! ビッグアナウンスメントが来ましたので、ちょっと...
Big announcement! Since we have a big announcement...
みんな一緒に、あの、どうぞと言ってくれますか？
Can everyone say "Here you go" together with me?
Okay! せーの...
Okay! Ready, set...
If you're ready, it's time for the huge announcement! Please take a look at this! どうぞー！
If you're ready, it's time for the huge announcement! Please take a look at this! Here you go!
What moves thy heart?
汝の心を動かすものはなんだ？
What is thy true desire?
真の望みはなんだ？
The fallen crown awaits from the shadows...
失われた王冠は影の中にて待つ
Her time has come,
彼女の刻は来たる
No one will ever question her rule again.
何人もその支配を拒むことはできない
2026.12.01
Hakos Baelz
1st Concert
i'll run the world, don't be absurd
it ain't a sin if you win
満ち足りない power お腹空いたわ
Unsatisfying power, I'm hungry
feed me more, i need more / oh, you'll be beggin' on all fours
自分次第生涯 ah ぼくの showtime
It's my life, ah, it's my showtime
Offer up thy soul and kneel.
魂を捧げ、探して平伏せ
For those who bow before her will...
彼女の意志に跪く者たちよ…
WITNESS HER LEGACY!
彼女の軌跡を目撃せよ
I'm finally doing it!
I can't believe it, guys! I did it! I am finally holding my very own...
...solo concert! ソロライブ決定です！やったー！
...solo concert! My solo live is confirmed! Yay!
I'm so happy! 本当にありがとうございました！
I'm so happy! Thank you so much!
It's gonna be happening on December 1st of this year! And the venue is none other than Kanadevia Hall in Tokyo!
えっと、なんと12月1日決定されました！ソロライブです！えっと、東京のKanadevia Hallで開催決定です！もう決定、決定ですよ、みんな！やっとだ！
It's confirmed for December 1st! My solo live! It's set for Kanadevia Hall in Tokyo! It's officially happening, everyone! Finally!
えっと、ライブのタイトルは REGALIA！This is the title of the live: REGALIA! I chose this title because I wanted this live to...
The title of the concert is REGALIA! This is the title of the live: REGALIA! I chose this title because I wanted this live to...
a symbol of my journey so far, and hopefully
a symbol for what is yet to come for a Bae takeover, you know.
えっと、まあ今回のライブタイトルは「REGALIA」です。
So, the title of this live concert is "REGALIA".
このライブはね、僕のこれまでの活動を象徴にするぞっていう意志を込めて、このタイトルにしました！
I chose this title with the intention of making this live concert a symbol of all my activities so far!
えっと、チケットやグッズの情報は後日発表しますので、もうしばらく待っててください。
Information about tickets and merchandise will be announced at a later date, so please wait a little longer.
Tickets and goods will be announced later on.
Please get hyped!
Ah! I did it! I did it!
And there's more!
In celebration of my first ever solo live, I am so happy to announce that my 2nd album, Mirror Mirror...
...is on its way!
Pre-orders will open today from 9 PM JST on the hololive production official shop.
そして、えっと、まあライブに向けてセカンドアルバムも、あの、出ます！「Mirror Mirror」というリリースが、あの、決定しました！
And so, ahead of the live concert, my second album will also be released! The release of "Mirror Mirror" has been confirmed!
えっと、日本時間で今日23日の夜9時から、えっと、ホロライブプロダクション公式ショップで、あの、まあ、受注開始されます！
Orders will start today, the 23rd, at 9 PM JST on the hololive production official shop!
ありがとうございます！本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much! Thank you very much!
Um, this album is so special to me.
Uh, it includes many songs... Um, actually, I wrote the lyrics of most of the songs on this album...
...with the theme of reflection, facing oneself, and this album was a project where I pushed myself to explore even more ways to express myself as an artist.
えっと、なんとですね、今回のアルバムの曲は大体全部歌詞の方は自分で書いてました。
And guess what? I wrote the lyrics for almost all the songs on this album myself.
えっと、まあ、リフレクション、自分との向き合いっていうテーマのもとで、まあアーティストとしての更なる表現力を、えっと、追求したい作品となってます！
Under the theme of "reflection" and facing oneself, this is a work where I aimed to pursue even greater artistic expression!
Uh, it also comes with a lot of uh album bonuses! You'll receive a special message letter with my signature, an original mirror sticker, and an artbook-style lyric booklet.
I'll be signing every single one of them, so please get it!
あとね、アルバム、え、購入特典もあります！サイン付きのスペシャルメッセージ、日本語版も英語版もあります。オリジナルミラースティッカーもあります。アートブック型の歌詞カードもあります。
Also, there are album purchase bonuses! Signed special message letters in both Japanese and English, original mirror stickers, and an artbook-style lyric booklet.
えー、もう買ってくれたみんなもサイン、サインをしますので、ぜひぜひよろしくお願いします。
I will be signing them for everyone who purchases it, so please check it out!
Uh, you can check the shop directly from YouTube, um, and both the album shipment and the digital release are scheduled for November 2nd JST.
So get hyped, stay tuned! There's a lot yet to come!
えっと、YouTubeからショップへアクセスできるので、ぜひチェックしてください。
You can access the shop directly from YouTube, so please be sure to check it out.
また、発送と、え、デジタルリリースは11月2日の予定となっております。楽しみにしてください。
Also, shipping and the digital release are scheduled for November 2nd. Please look forward to it!
そして、そして、そして！
And, and, AND!
Ah, I may have mentioned before that there is a new song releasing today, and that is right!
Right after this stream, the music video for "I found me", which is a very, very special song that is actually the first song I ever wrote from scratch, will be releasing, will be premiering after this stream!
えっと、この配信が終わったとき、ちょっとあのアルバムからの1曲「I found me」のMVが公開します！
When this stream ends, the MV for "I found me", one of the songs from the album, will premiere!
この曲は僕にとってめっちゃ大事な曲で、そして初めて1から書いた曲なんで、あの歌詞の方ね。なのでぜひぜひプレミア公開、よろしくお願いします！
This song is super important to me, and it's the first song where I wrote the lyrics from scratch. So please make sure to tune into the premiere!
The MV will be the opening video for my segment during YouTube Music Weekend!
Tada!
There's a lot! I'm so happy! My 5th anniversary and I get to be part of YouTube Music Weekend! Um, so it will be the opening video for my section which starts at 1:15 PM JST, so make sure to check it out!
このMVは、この後13時15分からスタートするYouTube Music Weekendで、僕のオープニングパートにもなっているので、ぜひぜひこれもチェックしてください！
This MV will also serve as the opening part of my segment for YouTube Music Weekend starting at 1:15 PM, so please check this out too!
Ah! I did it!
Ah, that's a lot of announcements. Are you guys being proud of me? I got a solo live!
Ah, that's a lot of announcements. Are you guys proud of me? I got a solo live!
You guys know why I've been so busy now! I've been busy...
I've been already doing a lot of prep for this amazing event that's happening, and I'll be sharing more details about the concert at a later date, so I really hope you look forward to it!
えっと、まあ、最近ちょっと僕ね、あの、疲れているプラスめっちゃ忙しくなった理由もこれになりますので、本当に頑張りますので、あの、楽しみにしててください！
So, the reason why I've been tired and super busy recently is because of this, so I'll do my absolute best, please look forward to it!
All right, with that being said, I think it's time to move on to the next segment.
ちょっと次のコーナーに行きたいと思います！
I'd like to move on to the next segment now!
Bae-Gemite Extravaganza!! Hakos Baelz 5th Anniversary Stream
[Title: Bae-Gemite Extravaganza!! Hakos Baelz 5th Anniversary Stream]
Welcome to...
ベンジマイト・コンコクションズ！イェーイ！
Bae-gemite Concoctions! Yeah!
見てる方も I think everyone knows, 一応自己紹介お願いしていいですか？
For those watching... I think everyone knows, but could you please introduce yourselves?
はい！もちろんでございます！じゃあ私から！
Yes! Of course! Well then, I'll go first!
ホロスターズの夕刻ロベルでーす！本日よろしくお願いします！
I'm Yukoku Roberu from Holostars! It's great to be here today!
なんか不穏な感じがね、しますけど。
Though I have a bad feeling about this...
そうですね。はい、怖いです。
Indeed. Yes, I'm scared.
怖くない... あ、怖くないもんね！
You're not scared... Oh, right, you're not!
頑張りたいと思います！よろしくお願いします！
I'll do my best! Nice to be here!
そして！
And next!
はい。あの... 理由も分からず呼び出されて、仕事だと思って来たら...
Yes. Um... I was called over without knowing why, thinking it was regular work...
なんだか不穏なスタジオでした。石川界人です！声優です！よろしくお願いします！
But I found myself in a very sketchy studio. I'm Kaito Ishikawa, a voice actor! Pleasure to be here!
そんな我々からも、ちょっとベーちゃんに言わなきゃいけないことあります！
From the two of us, there's something we have to tell you, Bae-chan!
ありますね！じゃあ行きましょう！はい！
Oh, absolutely! Alright, let's do it! Ready!
せーの！ソロライブ開催決定、おめでとう！
Ready, set... Congratulations on your upcoming solo live!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
あ、泣いちゃった！あらららら！嬉しいな！いや、すごいことよ！おめでとう！
Ah, she's crying! Oh my goodness! How sweet! Truly an amazing achievement! Congrats!
本当にありがとうございます！本当におめでとう！
Thank you so, so much! Big congratulations!
一VTuberファンとしてさ... ソロライブっていうのは夢じゃん！
As a fellow VTuber fan... A solo live is the ultimate dream!
夢ですよ！本当に！
It really is a dream come true!
なんかもう、熱いわー！
Wow, I'm getting all emotional here!
本当に素晴らしい！
It's truly wonderful!
えーっと、今日はね、チャレンジをやりたいと思います！
Well then, today we're going to do a challenge!
チャレンジ！いいですね、挑戦！
A challenge! Sounds great!
Today we've invited these two for a challenge called The Bae-gemite Concoctions.
まぁ、ロベルさんと界人さんは、もうベンジマイトの事ご存知でいらっしゃいますよね？
Well, Roberu-san and Kaito-san, you both already know all about Vegemite, right?
当たり前のように口にしてるけど... 我々にとっては...
You say that so casually, but for us...
我々にとっては、その... 呪いみたいなもんだから！その、怖いのよ結構！
For us, it's pretty much like a curse! Honestly, it's quite terrifying!
ベンジマイトと言ったらロベルさんですよね？
When you think Vegemite, you think Roberu-san, right?
正直このベンジマイトという道を作ってしまった発端の人物かも知れない。
To be honest, I might be the origin of this whole Vegemite madness.
ベーちゃんにベンジマイトって物があるよって教えてもらって、僕が実食配信みたいなのをするようになったんですよ。
Bae-chan told me about Vegemite, and I ended up doing a taste-test stream.
そこから始まったこの地獄は。多分。そして被害者たちが生まれて行った。
That's probably where this hell started, spawning a chain of new victims.
そう、で、一緒に配信で食レポみたいな配信もしたことがあって。
Yeah, and we even did a stream together doing food reviews on it.
それ以来なんで、こいつと対峙するのは3、4年ぶりくらいになりますかね、まあ。
So facing off against this stuff again... It's been about 3 or 4 years now.
じゃあもう味も忘れちゃってそうだもんね。
So you've probably forgotten the taste by now then?
うん、あのね... こびり付いてる。4年経っても消えない。味の記憶がこびり付いてる！
Well, you see... It's burned into my mind. Even after 4 years, the memory of that taste remains burned into my brain!
だから非常に怖さはあるけど、まあでもね、楽しみですよ。
So I'm pretty scared, but at the same time, I'm looking forward to it.
もっと元気そうに！楽しみです！イエーイ！
Say it with more energy! "I'm looking forward to it! Yeah!"
すごい楽しみ！食べたい！
I'm super excited! Can't wait to eat it!
そして界人さん！あの、ベンジマイトエピソードっていうことはありますか？
And Kaito-san! Do you have any Vegemite episodes or stories?
あー、ベンジマイトエピソードですか？非常に素晴らしい食材ですよね。
Ah, a Vegemite story? Well, it's a truly wonderful ingredient, isn't it?
もらってましたよね？ベーちゃんから。ホロごえで一緒になった時に、ベーちゃんからありがたいお土産をもらってましたよね？
You got some, right? From Bae-chan. When you appeared together on Hologoe, you got a lovely souvenir from her, right?
ええ。番組収録終了時にね、わざわざ楽屋にご挨拶いただいて...
Yes. After we finished recording the show, she came all the way to my green room to greet me...
なんて丁寧な方なんだろうと。素敵な方だなと思って、受け取って「これお土産です」と。
I thought, "What a polite and wonderful person!" She handed it to me and said, "This is a souvenir for you."
「ありがとうございます！あれですか？何かお菓子か何かですか？」「あ、ベンジマイトです」
I said, "Thank you so much! Is it snacks or something?" She replied, "Ah, it's Vegemite."
一応食べましたよ。おー偉い！食べました！？ちゃんと食べました。
I did eat it, by the way. / Oh, good boy! You ate it?! / Yes, I made sure to eat it.
なんて素晴らしい食材なんだろうって思いましたね！
I thought to myself, "What an incredible ingredient this is!"
素晴らしいんだ、やっぱり！ベンジマイトというのは！ベンジマイト素晴らしいです！
So it really is amazing after all! Vegemite is! / Vegemite is wonderful!
ちょっとね、記憶もあんまないと思いますので、ちょっと先、生で食べさせてもらいます！
Since you might not remember the exact taste, first, you're going to try it raw!
I gotta refresh their memories on the taste, so we do have Vegemite prepared in front of us.
大丈夫？いや、大丈夫じゃないです！お願いってわけじゃなくて...
Are you sure? / Well, it's not fine! And it's not a request...
5周年なんで... 命令です！食え！
Since it's my 5th anniversary... it's an order! EAT IT!
ソロライブも決まってるしな！そんなおめでたい人の命令じゃー！
Plus her solo live was just announced! How can I refuse an order from someone celebrating!
そうです！じゃあみんな... あ、怖い！
That's right! Alright everyone... Ah, terrifying!
せーの！乾杯！乾杯！
Ready, set... Cheers! / Cheers!
んー！美味っ！
Mmm! Delicious!
うわ、美味しい！
Wow, yummy!
美味ーい！美味いね！すっごい！
Yummy! So good, right?! Incredible!
大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay?
大丈夫じゃなさそ... え！もう飲み切っちゃいました！
Doesn't look okay... Wait! He already finished the whole bottle of water!
Ishikawa Kaito has finished one bottle of water. えっーと、早いっすね！
Ishikawa Kaito has finished one bottle of water. Wow, that was fast!
うわぁ... お水にとっても合うなぁ！
Whoa... It goes so remarkably well with water!
ああ、幸せ〜
Ah, bliss...
ああ〜
Ahhh...
大丈夫でしょうか？ちょっとあの、ロベル先輩の顔がえぐいっす。
Is everything okay? Um, Roberu-senpai's face looks intense.
泣いてる。
He's crying.
泣いてます？
Is he crying?
ほぼ泣いてる。
He's practically crying.
なんで？
Why?
美味し...
Delicious...
美味しすぎて？
Because it's too delicious?
美味しすぎてね...
It's too delicious...
Everybody is crying.
涙が止まらないね。
The tears won't stop.
ちょっとあの、進行役の... 多分両端死んでる。
Wait, the hosts... both ends are probably dead.
多分両端死んでると思って。
I thought both ends were dead.
はい。
Right.
はい、じゃあ説明行きます。
Okay, let's move on to the explanation.
We have the Vegemite Concoctions! So it is a tasting competition... I mean, tasting event.
To explain how it works, before today, Roberu-senpai, A-san, and I each came up with an ingredient that we thought would pair well with Vegemite.
And using all of our ideas as inspiration, a professional food coordinator... プロ!
And using all of our ideas as inspiration, a professional food coordinator... Professional!
えー！あ、そう！
Eh?! Ah, really?!
...professional food coordinator has created each dish with great care, and we're going to taste all of them and decide who came up with the best Vegemite Concoction!
なるほど。我々が選んだ食材でプロの方が...
I see. With the ingredients we picked, a professional...
すごく美味しくベジマイトを使って料理してくださってると。
has cooked them to be super delicious using Vegemite.
はい！
Yes!
なるほど。
I see.
これ信じられるの？
Can we really believe this?
いや、でもベジマイトって元々美味しいので...
Well, Vegemite is already delicious to begin with...
あ、そうだった。ごめんごめん。プロだからね。
Ah, that's right. Sorry, sorry. Since they're professionals.
プロだもんね。
They're professionals after all.
ベジマイト美味しいしね。
And Vegemite is tasty anyway.
なので、まあ美味しいプラス美味しいイコール美味しいじゃないですか。
So, tasty plus tasty equals tasty, right?
ああ、そうですね。美味しい。
Ah, that's true. Tasty.
美味しい。美味しい。
Tasty. Tasty.
ということで、あの、お互い何を選んだか全く分かんない。
So, none of us know at all what the others chose.
We don't know what the other has chosen, so it's going to be a surprise to us as well.
まぁ、早速始めようか。
Well, shall we get started right away?
あ、なるほど。始めます？
Ah, I see. Shall we start?
いいですよ。始めます？
Sounds good. Shall we begin?
一旦休憩時間欲しいかな？
Can I get a break real quick?
休憩？
A break?
胃の中でベジマイトが大暴れしてるんだわ。
Vegemite is rampaging inside my stomach.
うん、すごいよね。生きてる、これは。
Yeah, it's intense. It's alive, this stuff.
まあ、最初ちょっと何を言ったか...選んだか、ロベ先輩に聞きたくて...
Well, first I'd like to ask Roberu-senpai what he chose...
じゃあ僕から行きますか。
Shall I go first then?
最初にお願いします。
First, please go ahead.
わかりました。えーでは僕が選んだ食材はこちらでございます！
Understood. Well, the ingredient I chose is this right here!
牛タンです！
Beef tongue!
おー！
Ooh!
神！牛タンです！
God tier! It's beef tongue!
いいね！しょっぱいじゃないですか、ベジマイトって。
Nice! Isn't Vegemite salty?
うんうん。で、これはお肉に合うんじゃないかなと思ったんですよ、僕。
Yeah, yeah. So I thought this would pair well with meat.
おー！
Ooh!
そこで、単純に僕が牛タン食べたかったのもありまして...
Also, I simply just wanted to eat beef tongue...
アンケートを書いた時にね。なので今回、牛タンを選ばせていただきました。
when filling out the questionnaire. So this time, I selected beef tongue.
確かに！美味しくならないわけがない！
Indeed! There's no way it won't be delicious!
なるほどですね。
I see.
確かに焼肉系は上手そう！
Certainly, barbecue-style food sounds delicious!
Gyutan which is beef tongue, it is a yakiniku meat, and the reason he chose it was because, well, it's meat, Vegemite is salty, would be a good pairing, one would think. なるほどですね。
Gyutan which is beef tongue, it is a yakiniku meat, and the reason he chose it was because, well, it's meat, Vegemite is salty, would be a good pairing, one would think. I see.
はい。素晴らしい！
Yes. Wonderful!
これはお互いプロの方にお願いしているので...
Since we asked a professional to handle this...
何が出てくるでしょうか！
what will come out, I wonder!
ドキドキするな、これ。
This is getting nerve-wracking.
じゃあ、見ていきましょう！おねがいします！
Well then, let's take a look! Here we go!
うわー！おいしそう！
Woah! That looks so delicious!
うまそうだけど...めちゃめちゃ旨そう！
It looks tasty, but... it looks insanely delicious!
うっまそー！えっ、ちょっと待って、ベジマイトを発見できないですよね、ちょっと...
Looks so good! Wait, you can't really spot the Vegemite, can you? A bit...
え、すごい！どこか入ってる？
Eh, amazing! Is it in there somewhere?
これがね、一応「牛タン トルティーヤ」。
This is, for now, "Beef Tongue Tortilla".
トルティーヤ！ It's like a tortilla, it's like a wrap!
Tortilla! It's like a tortilla, it's like a wrap!
はいはいはいはい。
Right, right, right.
最近はね、タコスも流行ってますから。
Tacos have been popular lately, after all.
It's like this really... Yeah, ソースめちゃいい匂いするっすね。
It's like this really... Yeah, the sauce smells really nice.
ソースをかけたらいいのかな、これは？
Should we pour the sauce on it?
じゃあちょっと食べてみます。
Well, let me try eating it.
食べてみます。
Let me try it too.
ロベルさん、いっちゃってよ！
Roberu-san, go for it!
ちゃんとしてるな！すごい！いただきます！
It's properly made! Amazing! Bon appétit!
ちゃんとして...
Properly...
お！いってるいってるいってる！
Oh! He's eating it, eating it!
じゃあ僕も、いただきまーす！
Then I'll eat too! Bon appétit!
お、いい感じだぞ、ロベルさんが。
Oh, Roberu-san looks like he's enjoying it.
ロベさんどうよ？
Robe-san, how is it?
いや、あのね...言っていっすか？
Well, you know... can I say it?
全然美味しいっす！
It's completely delicious!
ベジマイトがどこにいるかわかんないっす！
I can't tell where the Vegemite is!
え、それは合ってるの？
Wait, is that supposed to happen?
わかんないっす！
I don't know!
ベーさんも美味い？
Is it good to you too, Bae?
美味い！
It's delicious!
今、2人が先に食べてリアクション見てから食べようと思って。
I thought I'd watch you two eat and react first before trying it.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
じゃあ大丈夫そうだね。いただきます！
Looks like it's safe then. Bon appétit!
こいつ...うっま！
This... is so delicious!
うまい！
Delicious!
本当にね、ベジマイトがどこにいるかマジで分からん！
Seriously, I really can't tell where the Vegemite is!
これ、これはまたプロの方からのあれがあるんですかね？
Is there a comment from the professional for this dish?
We have a comment from the food coordinator.
牛タンというのは、塩レモンダレでよく食べるところから発想いたしました。
The idea came from how beef tongue is often eaten with salt lemon sauce.
レモン塩ダレの塩部分をベジマイトにしました。
I replaced the salt part of the lemon salt sauce with Vegemite.
The idea came from the way beef tongue is commonly enjoyed with a salted lemon sauce, so instead of salt...
salt in the lemon sauce, we replaced it with Vegemite!
天才すぎる！
You're too much of a genius!
あ、そう？ なるほど、塩味だけを残したんだ。
Oh really? I see, so they kept just the saltiness.
でもベジマイトの風味はあまりないですか？
But isn't there much Vegemite flavor?
あ、確かに食べ終わった後ちょっと...
Ah, true, after eating it, a little bit...
It has like a slight like, it's like a refreshing breeze of Vegemite!
なんか優しい風みたいな。
Like a gentle breeze.
確かにね。
True.
ベジマイトが優しい風になることあるんだね。
So Vegemite can become a gentle breeze!
そうです！
That's right!
ベジマイトだけ食べたら岩で殴られたみたいな衝撃あったけど、
Eating Vegemite plain felt like getting hit with a rock,
こんな優しい風に調理できるんだね、ベジマイトってね。
but it's impressive it can be cooked into such a gentle breeze.
ベジマイトは優しいです。
Vegemite is gentle.
スゴ！ これ美味しいですね。
Amazing! This is delicious, isn't it?
では続いて、石川さん！
Now then, next up, Ishikawa-san!
We gonna move on with Ishikawa Kaito-san's ingredient.
やりましょう！ どんなものを選びました？
Let's do this! What kind of item did you choose?
じゃあ僕が選んだ食材、こちらです！ドン！
Well then, the ingredient I chose is this! Bam!
何？ 何ですか？
What is it?
納豆です！
It's natto!
イヤーーー！ 来たーーー！ 納豆！ キッツ！
Nooo! It's here! Natto! Harsh!
あれ、納豆好き？ / 納豆好きよ！ / ですよね。
Wait, do you like natto? / I like natto! / Right.
もうクセ強にはクセ強をぶつけたら、
I thought if you hit a strong flavor with another strong flavor,
こう何だろう、相乗効果みたいのするんじゃないかなと思って。
they'd create synergy or something.
I like the way he thinks! I like the way he thinks!
もうめちゃくちゃ素晴らしいと思います。
I think that's super wonderful.
そう、こちらを選ばせていただきました。日本の文化をぶつけてやるぜ！
Yes, that's why I chose this. I'm gonna hit it with Japanese culture!
This is Japanese culture! Yes!
Well, without further ado, what is the professional chef gonna do this time?
見ていきましょう！ お願いします！
Let's take a look! Please show us!
どうなっちゃうの、納豆は？
What's gonna happen to the natto?
おー！ えー！？ なんだこれ！？ どういうこと！？
Woah! Huh!? What is this!? What does this mean!?
うまそう！ え、何何何？ どういう食べ物...？
Looks delicious! Wait, what is it? What kind of food...?
あの、発酵生春巻き？ / 発酵生春巻き！
Um, Fermented Fresh Spring Rolls? / Fermented Fresh Spring Rolls!
生春巻きだ！ 発酵生春巻きって言葉も初めて聞きましたけど...
It's fresh spring rolls! I've never even heard the phrase 'fermented fresh spring rolls' before...
うわ、めっちゃトロトロしてる！
Woah, it's super slimy!
これもう一口でいくか。 / いっちゃってよ、Baeさん。
Should we take it in one bite? / Go ahead, Bae-san.
じゃ、つけていただきます。
Then, I'll dip it and eat.
うわ、めっちゃ... It's so slimy. いただきます！
Woah, so... It's so slimy. Bon appetit!
ん？ え、これ...
Hmm? Wait, this...
カイトさん。 / え？ / 先に言っておく。 / うん。
Kaito-san. / Eh? / I'll tell you in advance. / Yeah.
明確に『いる』。 / いる？
It's distinctly 'there'. / 'There'?
いる！ ...奴がいる。
It's there! That guy is in there.
いるなー！ いるー！
It's definitely there!
いやこれ、ソースにいるね。 / ソースか！ / うん。
No, wait, it's in the sauce. / It's the sauce?! / Yeah.
あれ？ 全然味しないんですけど。 / え？ ん？ / うまい！
Huh? I can't taste it at all though. / Eh? Huh? / It's delicious!
え！？ あれ、チェンジした？ / いや、いるよ！ / え？
What!? Wait, did it change? / No, it's there! / Eh?
あれが納豆に押しかけてるぐらいまだある。
It's so strong it's almost pushing back against the natto.
うん、わかる。相当だね。 / めっちゃ美味しい！
Yeah, I know. It's quite something. / It's super delicious!
うん、美味しい。普通に。 / 発酵同士なので相性が良いとのことでございます。
Yeah, it's delicious. Normally. / Since both are fermented, they go well together.
やっぱ塩味があるので何かのソースにできるとやっぱ塩味なんですね。
Because of the saltiness, if you make it into a sauce, it brings out that saltiness.
納豆のタレ、なるほど納豆のタレをベジマイトにしたらいいなと思い、マヨベースにしてその中にベジマイト入りタレを作りました。
"The natto sauce—I thought it'd be good to make the natto sauce with Vegemite, so I made a mayonnaise-based sauce mixed with Vegemite."
おー！ なるほど！
Oh! I see!
So, Vegemite's really nice and salty. I figured it could work as a base for sauce. Had the idea of replacing the sauce that comes with natto with Vegemite...
Made a mayonnaise-based sauce and mixed Vegemite into it!
うまい！ 食えちゃうんだよね！ / まあね！
It's good! You can actually eat it! / Well, yeah!
普通に美味しいです。 / This is so good. Oh my god. もうキラキラ！
It's plain delicious. / This is so good. Oh my god. It's glowing!
最後に行きますが... / はい。 / 食後の...
Moving on to the last one... / Yes. / After the meal...
何笑ってんの、おい！ 何ヘラヘラしてんの？
What are you laughing at, hey! Why are you smirking?
食後ってふつう何食べております？ / あ、食後の後？ / はい！ / ま、デザートみたいな。
What do you usually eat after a meal? / Ah, after a meal? / Yes! / Well, like dessert.
デザートですね！ 次は僕が選んだ食べ物になります。 / はい。
Dessert, right! Next is the food item I chose. / Yes.
We have reached the final dish. And normally at the end of every meal, you do have dessert. Australia...
トレジャー... ２つを組んだらどうなるか... / 宝物を２つ？
Treasures... What happens when you combine two of them... / Two treasures?
宝物２つを組んだらどうなっちゃうか、ちょっとめちゃくちゃ気になったんで...
I was really curious about what would happen if you combined two treasures...
えっと、最後の... 材料はこちらになります！ / 何？ 怖っ！
Um, the final... ingredient is this! / What? Terrifying!
ティムタムです！ / 誰？ 何？ ティムタムは？ その宝物知らないわ！
It's Tim Tams! / Who? What? Tim Tam? I don't know that treasure!
え、ティムタム知らないっすか？ / 知らないよ！
Eh, you don't know Tim Tam? / I don't!
これはオーストラリアのめちゃくちゃ有名なチョコレート、ビスケット... / あーなるほど！ あれね！
This is Australia's super famous chocolate biscuit... / Ah, I see! That one!
ティムタムです。 / ティムタムってお菓子ね！ / お菓子です！
It's Tim Tam. / Tim Tam is a snack! / It's a snack!
それをじゃあくれるんだ！ その、ベジマイトとかじゃなくて、単体でね。お土産でね。
So you're giving that to us! Not with Vegemite, but by itself. As a souvenir!
美味しいんだろうね！ ありがとう、クッキー、ビスケットは！ 本当に呼んでくれてありがとう、今日は！
Must be delicious! Thanks for the cookies/biscuits! Thanks so much for inviting us today!
ご褒美だよね！ 頑張った俺たちに対する！
It's a reward! For us who worked hard!
ということで、プロの方だったら、ティムタム＋ベジマイト...
So, if it's a professional chef, Tim Tam + Vegemite...
...美味しく作ってくれたのかなって...
...if they made it delicious for us...
なんで混ぜんだよ！
Why did you mix them?!
...思いましたので...
...so I thought...
You know, as a pro chef, I wanted to see what they can do, and I believe in their skills as a pro chef.
みんな行きましょう！お願いします！
Let's go, everyone! Please!
おっとっとっと…
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
どういうこと？ティラミス？
What do you mean? Tiramisu?
ティラミスじゃん！
It's tiramisu!
え、うまっ…え？どういうこと？
Huh, looks good... Huh? What's going on?
まあ、ちょっと一旦、発案者だしさ、先に食べてみてよ。 / はい、いただきます！
Well, since she came up with it, let her try it first. / Thanks for the food!
え、でもなんか…めちゃくちゃ美味しそう…すごいなー！
Wait, but it looks... so delicious. That's amazing!
うわー！これがベジマイト入ってる？いただきます。
Wow! Does this really have Vegemite in it? Bon appétit.
いや、わからん。警戒心が強くなりすぎてるだけかもしれん。
I don't know, maybe we're just being way too cautious.
普通にティラミスじゃん。
It's just a normal tiramisu.
いただきます！
Bon appétit!
なんか不思議そうな顔してない？
Doesn't she look a bit puzzled?
あれ？本当に入ってます？ベジマイト。
Wait, is Vegemite really in here?
え？入ってそうですよ？ / 美味しい！
Huh? Looks like it's in there. / Delicious!
え？普通にティラミスやん。 / いただきます。
Huh? It's just normal tiramisu. / Bon appétit.
ベーちゃんが一番分かってないまであるからな、ベジマイト。
Bae might actually be the one who understands Vegemite the least.
マジで？え？ベジマイトがいるのか？
Seriously? Huh? Is Vegemite actually in there?
確かに塩気あってうまっ！あ、いるわ！
There's definitely a salty taste and it's good! Ah, it's there!
いる！え、うまっ！え、美味しい！
It's there! Wow, it's good! It's delicious!
めっちゃうまいんだけどこれ！うま！
This is insanely good! So good!
Oh my god!
これお店出しましょう。 / We need a copyright, we need a patent, oh my god!
We should open a shop for this. / We need a copyright, we need a patent, oh my god!
えー、ティムタムと合う料理は思いつくのが大変でした。すみませんでした！本当に！
"Uh, coming up with a dish that pairs with Tim Tams was really tough. I'm sorry! Truly!"
ティムタム自体コーヒーが合いそうだと思ったのでティラミスにしました。
"I thought coffee would go well with Tim Tams, so I made tiramisu."
ティムタムのクッキーはサクサク感を活かしたいので、ティムタムを砕いてベジマイトを…
"To keep the crunchy texture of the Tim Tam, I crushed the Tim Tams and..."
ティムタムを砕いて、その中にベジマイト入れて、混ぜて、それをやってるんだ。
Crushing Tim Tams, putting Vegemite in it, mixing it up, and that's how it's made.
Apparently it was really hard to think of a dish that would pair well with Tim Tam, but Tim Tam goes well with coffee! Decided to make a tiramisu! Also wanted to keep the crunchy texture of the Tim Tam, so I crushed it up, soaked it with Vegemite...
すッげえうまい！
It's insanely good!
しかも、普通のティラミスより美味しくなってて。 / でしょー！
Plus, it actually tastes better than a normal tiramisu. / Right?!
塩気がいい味出してる。甘みが際立つというか。
The saltiness brings out a great flavor. It really highlights the sweetness.
でかつ生クリームの濃さとかが塩気によってちょっと中和される感もあって、めちゃくちゃくどくない。
And the richness of the heavy cream gets neutralized by the saltiness, so it's not heavy at all.
ねー！ / うまい！
Right?! / Delicious!
ティラミスにすることによってコーヒーの香りと苦味で、ティムタムのすっごい甘い感じも程よくまろやかになって…
By making it a tiramisu, the coffee aroma and bitterness smooth out the intense sweetness of the Tim Tam nicely...
これさ、ティムタムがうまいんじゃないの？
Isn't it just that Tim Tams are delicious?
でも！ティムタムの美味しさをちょっとね、昇華させたの！もうベジマイトのおかげなんで！
But! It elevated the taste of the Tim Tam! It's all thanks to Vegemite!
All because of Vegemite, Tim Tam's deliciousness has been, you know... / これうまっ！
All because of Vegemite, Tim Tam's deliciousness has been, you know... / This is so good!
すごいわ。プロってすごいな。あのベジマイトをこんなにできるの？
Pros are incredible. How can they transform that Vegemite into this?
「あのベジマイト」はやめてください！ / ごめんなさい！
Stop saying "that Vegemite"! / Sorry!
めっちゃ食ってますね。よかったです。 / 完食です！
You're eating so much. I'm glad. / Cleaned the plate!
あのね、全部うまかったな。総じて、今んとこ3個食べたけど。
You know, all of them were good overall. So far we've had three dishes.
えーと、ちょっと最後に、美味しさっていうか、三つ星の評価っていうか、やりたくて。
Uh, lastly, I want to do a rating out of three stars for how delicious they were.
I want to rate all of the different dishes. どれが一番美味しかったかちょっと決めたいので。
I want to rate all of the different dishes, to decide which one was the most delicious.
今まで食べた中で、どれが一番ベジマイトと相性が良かったかってことね。なるほど。
Out of what we've eaten, which one paired best with Vegemite. Got it.
じゃあまず、えっと、先輩の牛タンですね。
First, senior's beef tongue taco.
何星ですか？ How many stars are we giving the Gyutan?
How many stars are we giving the beef tongue?
俺は、二つ星かな。
For me, 2 stars.
まあ、俺も2かな。 / 僕も2だと思いましたね。めちゃくちゃ美味しかったです。
I'd give it a 2 as well. / I thought 2 as well. It was super delicious.
次が、フータさんの春巻きね。俺、1つ星かな！
Next is Fuuta's spring rolls. For me, 1 star!
ごめん、俺も1つ星かな。
Sorry, I think 1 star for me too.
自分は2.5なんですけど！あれ、めちゃくちゃ美味しい！
I'm giving it 2.5 though! What? It was super tasty!
いや、美味しかったんだけど… / 美味しかった！ / ベジマイトがいた！
No, it was good, but... / It was good! / Vegemite was there!
なんか風邪じゃなかった、ベジマイトが。まだ恋しいぐらいだった。
It wasn't just a trace, Vegemite was really present. A bit too noticeable.
たしかにそうですね。あれが好きだったかもしれないです、自分は。
That's true. I might have actually liked that part.
で、最後、僕のティラミス、ティムタム何星ですか？
And lastly, how many stars for my Tiramisu Tim Tam?
3！ / 3！ / 僕も3！勝ったー！
3! / 3! / 3 for me too! I won!
三つ星すぎ！
Solid 3 stars!
ベジマイトがティムタムの甘さを活かしてた。 / ですよね！
The Vegemite actually highlighted the sweetness of the Tim Tam. / Right?!
流石ベジマイトです。 / もうこのティラミスが、2つの宝が合わさったことによって、たった一つの大秘宝になってた！
As expected of Vegemite. / Combining these two treasures into a single grand treasure!
あいつオーストラリアから何か貰おうとしてるな！
That guy's trying to get sponsored by Australia!
僕アニメ声優をやってましてね！
I work as an anime voice actor, you know!
すごく
Really...
企画、まあ、こういう感じだったんですけど...
The plan was originally like this, but...
ちょっとベジマイトの最初のイメージ変わりました。
...my initial image of Vegemite has changed a bit.
あ、最初に食べてみてからっと。
Oh, compared to when you first tried it?
感想、まあね、感想変わりました、もしかして。
Your, well, impression changed, perhaps?
なんか物によってはというか...
Well, depending on what it's paired with...
こんなにもやり方次第でベジマイトの味が変化していくものなのかとか...
...or how it's prepared, the flavor of Vegemite can change this much...
なんか色々な使い方のがあるんだなって意味でびっくりはしたね。
I was really surprised by how many different ways there are to use it.
うん、すごくびっくりしました、僕、ベジマイト。
Yeah, I was really surprised by Vegemite.
ロベ先輩、ショック！好きになりました？
Robe-senpai is shocked! Did you end up liking it?
はい。
Yes.
好きになりました？
Did you come to like it?
はい。
Yes.
好きになりました？
Did you come to like it?
はい、ありがとうございます。はい、ベジマイト...
Yes, thank you. Yes, Vegemite...
I like Vegemite.
いや、"like" じゃない。
No, not "like".
I love Vegemite.
あ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you so much!
Yeah.
はい！
Yes!
ありがとうございます！はい！
Thank you very much! Yes!
で、界人さんは？
And how about you, Kaito-san?
俺は、やっぱこう最初の印象は...
For me, my initial impression was...
もういろんな味がすることで、こう、なんだろう、びっくりするな...
...like, having so many flavors hit at once makes you go, "Whoa..."
なんか...
Like...
みんなショックやん！
Everyone was in shock!
...っていう印象だったんだけど...
...that was my impression, but...
はい。
Yes.
こんなに色んな調理の仕方すると...
...when you cook it in so many different ways...
ベジマイトの色んな味がするっていういいところを、ちょっとずつこう、拾っていけるんだと思って。
...you can pick out the good aspects of Vegemite's complex flavor profile step by step.
無限の可能性がある食材だという風に思いましたね。
I realized it's an ingredient with infinite possibilities.
好きですか？好きになりました？
Do you like it? Did you come to like it?
あー... いや、まあね...
Ah... Well, you know...
好きになりました？
Did you come to like it?
あの、あんまり俺、嘘...
Umm, I don't really like to lie...
好きになりました？
Did you come to like it?
Yes.
え？
Eh?
はい。
Yes.
え？
Eh?
好きになりました？
Did you come to like it?
はい！
YES!
ざいます！
Thank you!
えっーと、まあ...
Umm, well...
みんなもね、気になったら、もうぜひぜひベジマイトを自分で買って、自分でちょっとね...
Everyone, if you're curious, please buy some Vegemite and try it yourself...
調理技術に自信があれば...
If you're confident in your cooking skills...
If you want to find your own ways to enjoy Vegemite, I feel like, you know, it'll be such a great experience.
瓶はちょっと... 瓶はちょっと...
The jar on its own is a bit... The jar on its own is a bit...
まあまあ何はともあれ、べーちゃん、本当にあの...
Well anyway, Bae-chan, really...
あ、本当に...
Ah, really...
マジで5周年おめでとう！
Seriously, congratulations on 5 years!
おめでとうございます！
Congratulations!
ライブ開催もね。
And on the live show too!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ありがとうございます！来てくださってありがとうございます！
Thank you so much! Thank you for coming today!
頑張ってね。
Do your best!
Thank you to the two of them for coming. I can't believe this is how I'm celebrating my 5th year anniversary, but I'm so glad it is.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
じゃ、せーの...
Okay, ready, set...
おつベジマイト！
Otsu-Vegemite!
三つ星！
Three stars!
良い子は真似しないでね！
Good kids, don't try this at home!
And with that, we're almost at the end of my anniversary stream!
I hope you all had fun today!
いや、もう、終わりたくないね！
Ah, man, I don't want it to end!
本当に5周年ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for 5 years!
Thank you so much for all the support for 5 years!
We're not done yet!
まだね、おしらせ一事残ってます！
We still have one last announcement left!
なと！
And that is!
グッズが出ます！
Merchandise is coming out!
We still have the last announcement! 5th Anniversary merch!
We've got some really cool merch this time, too!
Please check it out!
どうぞ！
Here you go!
5th anniversary merch, of course it had to be the Monochrome Dancer...
...and Rat Dancer! This is the Best Oshi merch!
This beautiful artwork was done by Hyde-sensei!
Hyde-sensei に書いていただきました！
Hyde-sensei drew this for us!
今回のグッズのテーマは、まあやっぱり今年発表したモノクロームダンサー衣装と...
The theme for this merch set, well, is of course the Monochrome Dancer outfit revealed this year...
...バックダンサーの、まあ、お二人ですね！はい！
...and the back dancers, the two of them! Yes!
Let's go through each item one by one!
First up is this!
First is the acrylic stand! "Best Oshi" Acrylic Stand!
ベスト推しアクリルスタンドですね！
It's the "Best Oshi" acrylic stand!
It's so cool!
It features the amazing artwork that Hyde did, and I think it features... It's all the best oshi...
まあ、ベスト推し僕ですよね！僕ですね！
Well, the best oshi is me, right? It's me!
Yes, of course! The best oshi, everyone's favorite oshi is me!
But it does have the two back dancers in the back cause I know you guys love them!
I'm so obsessed with how it turned out! めっちゃかっこいい感じになったと思います！
I'm so obsessed with how it turned out! I think it turned out super cool!
Next up is...
The "Rat Dancer" Jacket!
やっとですね！"Rat Dancer" Jacket is becoming official merch!
Finally! The "Rat Dancer" jacket is becoming official merch!
グッズになりました、ジャケットが！
The jacket became official merch!
いや、本当に素晴らしい！
Wow, it's really wonderful!
We've made a few adjustments so it's comfortable and easy to wear in everyday life.
ちょっとね、このジャケットは着用しやすいよ。ちょっと調整をしたんですけど、本当にかっこいいジャケットになったと思います！
Yeah, this jacket is really easy to wear. We made some tweaks, and I think it turned out to be a really cool jacket!
なんとね、This time, the 5th Anniversary merch doesn't have as many items, just because I know there's a lot happening.
You know, this time, the 5th Anniversary merch doesn't have as many items, just because I know there's a lot happening.
We've got the album, you know, and also we've got the live and everything, so it's only these two items.
But if you pick up the complete merch set, you will also get THIS!
You will get a replica sticker with a signature and an exclusive ASMR voice pack as a special bonus! Thank you so much for always supporting me!
えーと、もしね、今回ちょっとね、色、たくさん告知とかお知せがあったんですけど...
Umm, if, well, today there were a lot of announcements and notifications...
今回の、あの、5周年グッズは2点になります。
This time, the 5th anniversary merch set consists of two items.
もしセット買ってくれている方に、えっと、複製サイン入りのステッカーと、
For those who buy the full set, as a bonus...
ASMRボイスが特典についてきます！
...it comes with a replicated autograph sticker and an ASMR Voice Pack!
The title of the voice pack is "Be my model!"
We check out the sample of the Red Dancing Jacket together,
and there's even a scene where we actually recorded using the real jacket sample, so I hope you'll give it a listen!
えーっと、まあ、こちらのボイスのタイトルは「ボクのモデルになって！」
Um, well, the title of this voice pack is "Be my model!"
先ほどね、紹介した、ジャケットのサンプルを使って、
Using the jacket sample I introduced earlier,
一緒になんかね、ボイスのシチュエーションを作ったっていうか、収録しました。
we recorded a situation together for the voice pack.
お恥ずかしがりながら、ぜひ聴いてて下さい。
Though I'm a bit embarrassed, please give it a listen!
You can access the shop directly from YouTube, so be sure to check it out!
YouTubeからショップへアクセスできるので、チェックしてください！
You can access the shop directly from YouTube, so please check it out!
はい！ That was the actual final announcement.
Yes! That was the actual final announcement.
But before I go, there's one more thing I wanted to do with you all.
And in order to do that, I need to first...
変身！
Transform!
はい、アイドルベア来ました！
Okay, Idol Bae is here!
I just wanted to sing one song before we end today's stream.
I just want to say thank you so much for 5 years. I'll continue doing my best.
Thank you so much for everything you've given me, and I will do my best.
5年間本当にありがとうございました。
Thank you so much for these 5 years.
ちょっと最後にね、1曲歌いたいなと思ってます。
I'd like to sing one last song at the end.
気持ちを込めてこれからも頑張りたいと思いますので、最後に1曲聴いてください！
Putting my feelings into it, I want to keep doing my best, so please listen to this last song!
Music, スタート！
Music, start!
誇り高きアイドルだ！
A proud idol!
私のこと知ってますか？ 可愛く見えてますか？
Do you know who I am? Do I look cute to you?
私の歌どうだろうな うまく歌えてますか？
What do you think about my singing? Did I manage to sing well?
衣装だとかメイクだとか 可愛く見えてますか？
My costume and makeup... Do I look cute wearing them?
振付とかファンサとかも 喜んでもらえますか？
My dancing and fan service... Do they make you happy?
手は冷たくなって 足は震える
My hands are getting cold, and my legs are shaking.
それでも戦いたい アイドルだから
Even so, I still want to keep fighting because I'm an idol!
バカにする奴は嫌いだ
I hate people who make fun of me!
見下されるのも嫌いだ
I don't like to be looked down on either!
“アイドルなんか”という言葉を 見てもいないくせに言うな
Don't say words like "just an idol" when you haven't even actually seen us!
頑張りを当然と言うな
Don't take my hard work for granted!
イメージとか強制するな
Don't force an image on me!
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は この世で一番大嫌いだ
Words like "just an idol" are the one thing I hate most in this world!
プライベート見えないから 分からないと思います
Because you can't see my private life, I don't think you'd know this side of me...
性格とか悪い方です 騙しちゃっていますか？
My personality is actually pretty bad. Did I manage to fool you?
でも本気です 本気なんです ありのままの私を
But it's the truth, I'm being serious! Please love me the way I am...
好きになって 推して下さい それってワガママですか？
...and become my fan. Is that a selfish thing to ask?
きっと可愛くない 全部分かってる
I'm sure that I'm not cute, I already knew it all.
それでも好かれてたい アイドルだから
Even so, I still want to be liked because I'm an idol!
皮肉言う奴は嫌いだ
I hate people who say sarcastic things!
言い訳ばかりも嫌いだ
I hate people who keep making excuses too!
“こんなもんか”という言葉を 軽々しく口にするな
Don't just say words like "is that all?" so lightly!
勝手に限界決めるな
Don't just set limits on me!
笑い者になんてするな
Don't make a fool out of me!
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は この世で一番大嫌いだ
Words like "just an idol" are the one thing I hate most in this world!
向かい風を切り裂け
Cutting through the headwinds...
誇り高きアイドル
...a proud idol...
目指そうぜ
Let's aim to be one!
応援がなければ 活動できない
Without all the support, I can't do any work.
好きな事ばかりじゃ 生きてはいけない
I can't live my life by doing only the things that I like.
元気あげるはずが もらってばかりだし
Even though I'm supposed to give you energy, I continue to receive it instead...
恩返しできる日まで 待ってて
Until the day I can repay you comes, wait for me!
待っててね！ 12月、約束だ！
Wait for me, okay?! December, it's a promise!
歓声が減っても
Even if the cheers fade,
飽きられちゃっても
or people grow tired of me,
それでも笑っていたい アイドルだから
I still want to smile, because I'm an idol.
熱いファンの愛があって
With the passionate love of the fans,
スタッフさんの愛があって
with the love of the staff,
いつも家族の愛があって
and with the constant love of my family,
生きてる
I'm living...
アイドル
...as an idol!
バカにする奴は嫌いだ
I hate those who make fun of me,
見下されるのも嫌いだ
and I hate being looked down upon.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉を
Don't say words like "just an idol"...
見てもないくせに言うな
...when you haven't even seen what I do!
頑張りを当然と言うな
Don't take my effort for granted,
イメージとか強制するな
and don't force your expectations on me.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は
Words like "just an idol"...
この世で一番大嫌いだ
...are what I hate most in this world!
ありがとうねー！
Thank you so much!
MV見てね！ MV見てね！
Check out the MV! Check out the MV!
Thank you everyone for being here!
Don't forget to check out YouTube Music Weekend right after this,
and also give a lot of love to I FOUND ME and ME!
この後もみんな見てね！
Make sure to watch what comes next, everyone!
これからも頑張るから応援よろしくお願いします！
I'll keep doing my best from now on, so please keep supporting me!
Thank you so much for 5 years!
I'll keep doing my best!
Bye-bye!
ほんとうに... ほんとうに... ありがとう♡
Thank you so, so much... ♡